<Module xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1" xmlns:htm="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section" boilerplate="yes" target-product="Server Virtualization Systems" name="Server Virtualization">

    <PPReference>
       <ReferenceTable>
            <PPVersion>1.1</PPVersion>
            <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
            <PPPubDate>2021-06-14</PPPubDate>
            <Keywords>Server Virtualization</Keywords>
        </ReferenceTable>
    </PPReference>

    <RevisionHistory>
        <entry>
            <version>1.0</version>
            <date>2016-11-17</date>
            <subject>Initial Publication as an Extended Package</subject>
        </entry>
        <entry>
            <version>1.1</version>
            <date>2020-06-14</date>
            <subject>Publication as a PP-Module</subject>
        </entry>
    </RevisionHistory>
    
    <!-- 1. Introduction -->
    <section id="Introduction" title="Introduction">

     	<!-- 1.1 Overview -->
    
	<section id="overview" title="Overview">
          The scope of this PP-Module is to define the security functionality of a Server Virtualization product in
          terms of [CC] and to define functional and assurance requirements for such products. This PP-Module is not 
          complete in itself, but rather is intended for use with the following Base-PP:
	      
	      <htm:ul>
		      <htm:li>Protection Profile for Virtualization, Version 1.1, 14 Jun 2021.</htm:li>
	      </htm:ul>

	  This Base-PP is valid because Server Virtualization is a specific type of Virtualization System and is expected to
          implement security functionality that is not common to all Virtualization Systems. One additional SFR
          has been defined in this PP-Module to define security functionality that is unique to this
          particular type of Virtualization System.        
      </section>

	<!-- 1.2 Terms -->
      <tech-terms>
	 <suppress>Distributed TOE</suppress>
        <term full="Administrator">Administrators perform management activities on the VS. These management functions 
          do not include administration of software running within Guest VMs, such as the Guest OS. Administrators need
          not be human as in the case of embedded or headless VMs. Administrators are often nothing more than software
          entities that operate within the VM.</term>
      <term full="Domain">A Domain or Information Domain is a policy construct that groups together execution 
          environments and networks by sensitivity of information and access control policy. For example, classification
          levels represent information domains. Within classification levels, there might be other domains representing
          communities of interest or coalitions. In the context of a VS, information domains are generally implemented
          as collections of VMs connected by virtual networks. The VS itself can be considered an Information Domain, 
          as can its Management Subsystem.</term>
      <term full="Guest Operating System (OS)">An operating system that runs within a Guest VM.</term>
      <term full="Guest VM">A Guest VM is a VM that contains a virtual environment for the execution of an independent
          computing system. Virtual environments execute mission workloads and implement customer-specific client or
          server functionality in Guest VMs, such as a web server or desktop productivity applications.</term>
     <term full="Host Operating System (OS)">An operating system onto which a VS is installed. Relative to the VS, 
          the Host OS is part of the Platform.</term>
      <term full="Hypervisor">The Hypervisor is part of the VMM. It is the software executive of the physical platform
          of a VS. A Hypervisor’s primary function is to mediate access to all CPU and memory resources, but it is also
          responsible for either the direct management or the delegation of the management of all other hardware
          devices on the hardware platform.</term>
      <term full="Hypercall">An API function that allows VM-aware software running within a VM to invoke VMM functionality.</term>
      <term full="Management Subsystem">Components of the VS that allow VS Administrators to configure and manage the
          VMM, as well as configure Guest VMs. VMM management functions include VM configuration, virtualized network
          configuration, and allocation of physical resources.</term>
      <term abbr="OS" full="Operating System"/>
      <term full="Platform">The hardware, firmware, and software environment into which a VS is installed and executes.</term>
      <term full="User">Users operate Guest VMs and are subject to configuration policies applied to the VS by Administrators.
		      Users need not be human as in the case of embedded or headless VMs, users are often nothing more than software
		      entities that operate within the VM.</term>
      <term full="Virtual Machine" abbr="VM">A Virtual Machine is a virtualized hardware environment in which an operating system
		      may execute.</term>
      <term full="Virtual Machine Manager" abbr="VMM">A VMM is a collection of software components responsible for enabling VMs to
		      function as expected by the software executing within them. Generally, the VMM consists of a Hypervisor, Service 
		      VMs, and other components of the VS, such as virtual devices, binary translation systems, and physical device
		      drivers. It manages concurrent execution of all VMs and virtualizes platform resources as needed.</term>
      <term full="Virtualization System" abbr="VS">A software product that enables multiple independent computing systems to 
		      execute on the same physical hardware platform without interference from one another. For the purposes of this 
		      document, the VS consists of a Virtual Machine Manager (VMM), Virtual Machine abstractions, a management subsystem,
		      and other components.</term>
    </tech-terms>
  
	<!-- 1.3 Compliant Targets of Evaluation -->
      <section id="targets" title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation">
        Server Virtualization, for the purposes of this Module, refers to a virtualization system that implements 
        virtualized hardware components on server-class hardware. It creates a virtualized hardware environment for 
        each instance of an operating system (virtual machines or VMs) permitting these environments to execute
        concurrently while maintaining isolation and the appearance of exclusive control over assigned computing
        resources. Each VM instance supports applications such as file servers, web servers, and mail servers. Server
        virtualization may also support client operating systems in a virtual desktop or thin-client environment.
        Typically, virtualized servers provide services to remote clients from a data center, and are generally not
	directly accessible by non-administrative users.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
	A TOE that claims conformance with this PP-Module must also claim conformance to the Protection Profile 
	for Virtualization. And a TOE that claims conformance with the Protection Profile for Virtualization
	must also claim conformance either to this Module or to the PP-Module for Client Virtualization.
        
	<!-- 1.3.1 TOE Boundary -->
        <section id="TOEboundary" title="TOE Boundary">
          The TOE boundary is the same as that which is defined for a Virtualization System in the
		Base-PP. 
        </section>   
      </section>
      
	<!-- 1.4 Use Cases -->
      <section id="usecase" title="Use Cases">
        Requirements in this PP-Module are designed to address the security problem in the following use cases. The description of these use
	      cases provides examples for how the TOE and its Operational Environment could support the functionality 
	      required by this PP-Module.
        <usecases>
          <usecase title="Virtualized Servers" id="virtservers">
            <description>
              A platform for virtualized instances of network-based services traditionally executed on separate hardware platforms, such as
              web servers, file servers, and mail servers.                
            </description>
          </usecase>
          <usecase title="Virtualized Network Infrastructure" id="networkinfra">
            <description>
               A platform for virtualized instances of routers, switches, and other network infrastructure.
            </description>
          </usecase>
          <usecase title="Virtualized Enterprise User Environments" id="userenv">
             <description>
                A platform for the server back-end of virtual desktop or thin-client implementations where actual computation 
		     occurs in server-based VMs and users interact through a client. The client application is 
		     not covered by this PP-Module.               
	     </description>
          </usecase>
        </usecases>
      </section>
    </section>
  
	<!-- 2. Conformance Claims -->
    <section id="conf" title="Conformance Claims">
    <cclaims>
        <cclaim name="Conformance Statement">
          <description> 
            This PP-Module inherits exact conformance as required from the Virtualization PP and as defined in the
            CC and CEM addenda for Exact Conformance, Selection-Based SFRs, and Optional SFRs (dated May 2017).
            <htm:br/><htm:br/> 
	    There are no other PP-Modules that are allowed to be specified in a PP-Configuration with this PP-Module.
          </description>
        </cclaim>
        <cclaim name="CC Conformance Claims">
          <description>
                This PP-Module is conformant to Parts 2 (extended) and 3 (extended) of Common Criteria Version 3.1, 
                Release 5 [CC].
          </description>
        </cclaim>
      </cclaims>
    </section>
  
	<!-- 3. Security Problem Description -->
    <section id="spd" title="Security Problem Description">
      The security problem is described in terms of the threats that the TOE is expected to address, assumptions
      about its operational environment, and any organizational security policies that the TOE is expected to 
      enforce.<htm:br/>
	    
	<!-- 3.1 Threats -->
      <section id="threats" title="Threats">
        This PP defines no additional threats beyond those defined in the Base-PP. Note however that the
        SFRs defined in this PP-Module will assist in the mitigation of the following threats defined in the Base-PP:   
	      <threats>
	      <threat name="T.UNAUTHORIZED_UPDATE">
		      <description>See Virtualization PP, Section 3.1.</description>
		      <consistency-rationale>This threat comes directly from the Base-PP.</consistency-rationale>
		      <objective-refer ref="O.VMM_INTEGRITY">
			      <rationale>Integrity of a Virtualization System can be maintained by ensuring that the only way to modify 
				      the VS is through a trusted update process initiated by an authorized Administrator
				      as required by FMT_MOF_EXT.
			      </rationale>
		      </objective-refer>
	      </threat>
	      <threat name="T.UNAUTHORIZED_ACCESS">
		      <description>See Virtualization PP, Section 3.1.</description>
		      <consistency-rationale>This threat comes directly from the Base-PP.</consistency-rationale>
		      <objective-refer ref="O.MANAGEMENT_ACCESS">
			      <rationale>Access to management functions must be limited to authorized Administrators as
				      managed through controls required by FMT_MOF_EXT.1.</rationale>
		      </objective-refer>
	      </threat>		      
	      </threats>
      </section>
	    
	<!-- 3.2 Assumptions -->
      <sec:Assumptions> <assumptions/> </sec:Assumptions>
	    
	 <!-- 3.3 Organizational Security Policies -->
      <sec:Organizational_Security_Policies> <OSPs/> </sec:Organizational_Security_Policies>
    </section>
	
	<!-- 4. Security Objectives -->
    <section id="objectives" title="Security Objectives">
	    
	    <!-- 4.1 Security Objectives for the TOE -->
        <section id="TOEobjectives" title="Security Objectives for the TOE">
            This Module defines no additional TOE security objectives beyond those defined in the Base-PP. Note however 
		that the SFR defined in this Module will assist in the achievement of the following objectives defined in the Base-PP:    
		<SOs>
			<SO name="O.VMM_INTEGRITY">
				<description>See Virtualization PP, Section 4.1.</description>
				<consistency-rationale>This objective comes directly from the Base-PP.</consistency-rationale>
				<addressed-by>FMT_MOF_EXT.1</addressed-by>
				<rationale>Integrity of a Virtualization System can be maintained by ensuring that the only way to modify 
				      the VS is through a trusted update process initiated by an authorized Administrator
				      as required by FMT_MOF_EXT.1.</rationale>
			</SO>
			<SO name="O.MANAGEMENT_ACCESS">
				<description>See Virtualization PP, Section 4.1.</description>
				<consistency-rationale>This objective comes directly from the Base-PP.</consistency-rationale>
				<addressed-by>FMT_MOF_EXT.1</addressed-by>
				<rationale>Access to management functions must be limited to authorized Administrators as
				      managed through controls required by FMT_MOF_EXT.1.</rationale>
			</SO>
		</SOs>
        </section>
	
	<!-- 4.2 Security Objectives for the Operational Environment -->
        <section id="objectivesEnvironment" title="Security Objectives for the Operational Environment">
            Because this Module does not define any additional assumptions or organizational security policies, there are no additional 
		security objectives for the Operational Environment to satisfy.        
        </section>
	    
	 <!-- 4.3 Security Objectives Rationale -->
	<section title="Security Objectives Rationale" id="rationale">
         <!-- Note: This section should remain empty and is populated from the rationale tags in the previous sections.  -->
         </section>
    </section>
	
	<!-- 5. Security Requirements -->
    <section id="sfr" title="Security Requirements">
	    
	 <!-- 5.1 Virtualization PP -->
	<base-pp id="b-virt">
          <git><url>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/commoncriteria/virtualization</url>
	  <branch>master</branch></git>
          <url>https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?PPID=408&amp;id=408</url>

		<!-- 5.1 Virtualization PP Security Functional Requirements Direction -->
		<sec-func-req-dir>
			In a PP-Configuration that includes the Virtualization PP, the TOE is expected to rely on some of the 
			security functions implemented by the Virtualization System as a whole and evaluated against the Base-PP.
			This section describes any modifications that the ST author must make to Base-PP SFRs to satisfy the 
			required VS functionality.
		</sec-func-req-dir>

		<!-- 5.1.1 Modified SFRs -->	
		<modified-sfrs/> 
		<additional-sfrs/>
			
		<!-- Consistency Rationale -->
		<!-- Consistency of TOE Type -->
		<con-toe>When this PP-Module is used to extend the Virtualization PP, the TOE type for
		        the overall TOE is still a Virtualization System. The TOE boundary does not change.
		</con-toe>
	
		<con-sec-prob/>
		<con-obj/>
		<con-op-en/>
		<con-mod ref="T.UNAUTHORIZED_UPDATE">This threat applies to functionality that is described in the Base-PP, but is 
			managed through functionality described in this PP-module.</con-mod>
		<con-mod ref="T.UNAUTHORIZED_ACCESS">This threat applies to functionality that is described in the Base-PP, but is 
			managed through functionality described in this PP-module.</con-mod>
		
	</base-pp>
	
	 <!-- 5.2 TOE Security Functional Requirements -->
	  <man-sfrs>	
		  
  	    <section id="ss-audit-table" title="Auditable Events for Mandatory SFRs">
        	<audit-table table="mandatory" id="at-mandatory">
  	     		<htm:br/><htm:b><ctr ctr-type="Table" pre="Table " id="atref-mandatory">: Auditable Events for Mandatory SFRs</ctr></htm:b>
	  	</audit-table>
	    </section>
		  
            <section id="management-fmt" title="Security Management (FMT)">
		<ext-comp-def fam-id="FMT_MOF_EXT" title="Management of Security Functions Behavior">
           		<mod-def> This family is defined in the Virtualization PP. This Module augments the extended family by adding one
				additional component, FMT_MOF_EXT.1. 
			</mod-def>		
		</ext-comp-def>
		<f-component cc-id="fmt_mof_ext.1" name="Management of Security Functions Behavior">
			<consistency-rationale>This SFR requires the Server Virtualization product to manage security functionality
				defined in the Virtualization PP in FPT_TUD_EXT.1, FIA_PMG_EXT.1, FDP_VNC_EXT.1, FDP_PPR_EXT.1, FDP_VMS_EXT.1,
				FIA_UAU.5, FPT_RDM_EXT.1, FCS_CKM.1, FCS_CKM.2, FCS_COP.1/HASH, FIA_AFL_EXT.1, 
				FAU_STG_EXT.1, FIA_X509_EXT.2.2, and FTA_TAB.1.</consistency-rationale>
	            	<comp-lev>defines required management functions and responsibilities.</comp-lev>
		        <management>There are no additional management functions beyond those already described in FMT_MOF_EXT.1.</management>
           		<audit>There are no auditable events defined for this SFR.</audit>
<!--            		<dependencies>FPT_TUD_EXT.1, FIA_PMG_EXT.1, FDP_VNC_EXT.1, FDP_VMS_EXT.1,
				FPT_HCL_EXT.1, FPT_RDM_EXT.1, FIA_AFL_EXT.1, and FTA_TAB.1.</dependencies>	 -->
			<dependencies>No other dependencies.</dependencies>
                     	<f-element id="fmt-mof-ext-1e1">
                        	<title>The TSF shall be capable of supporting 
                            		<selectables>
	                                	<selectable>local</selectable>
        	                        	<selectable id="sel-mof-1e1-remote-server">remote</selectable>    <!-- This selection brings in FTP_TRP in the base -->
                            		</selectables> administration.
                        	</title>
                        <note role="application">Selection of “remote” requires the selection-based requirement FTP_TRP.1 defined in the Base-PP to be included in the ST.</note>
                    </f-element>
                    <f-element id="fmt-mof-ext-1e2">
                        <title>The TSF shall be capable of performing the following management functions, [<htm:i>controlled by an Administrator 
				or User as shown in <xref to="manfunc"/>, based on the following key:</htm:i><htm:p/>
                            <htm:ul style="list-style: none;">
                                <htm:li>X = Mandatory (TOE must provide that function to that role)</htm:li><htm:br/>
                                <htm:li>O = Optional (TOE may or may not provide that function to that role)</htm:li><htm:br/>
                                <htm:li>N = Not Permitted (TOE must not provide that function to that role)</htm:li><htm:br/>
                                <htm:li>S = Selection-Based (TOE must provide that function to that role if the TOE claims a particular 
					selection-based SFR)</htm:li><htm:br/>
                            </htm:ul>
                            <htm:center><htm:h4><ctr ctr-type="Table" pre="Table " id="manfunc">: Server Virtualization Management Functions</ctr></htm:h4></htm:center>
                            <htm:table>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:th>Number</htm:th> 
                                    <htm:th>Function</htm:th> 
                                    <htm:th>Admin</htm:th> 
                                    <htm:th>User</htm:th> 
                                    <htm:th>Notes (all SFR references are from the Base-PP</htm:th> 
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>1</htm:td> 
                                    <htm:td>Ability to update the Virtualization System</htm:td> 
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td> 
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td> 
                                    <htm:td>See FPT_TUD_EXT.1</htm:td> 
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>2</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td><selectables>
					    <selectable id="sel-mf-pwd-policy">Ability to configure Administrator password policy as defined in FIA_PMG_EXT.1</selectable>
					    <selectable>Not applicable.</selectable></selectables></htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>S</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Must be selected if ST includes FIA_PMG_EXT.1.</htm:td>
				    <!-- sel "sel-mf-2" if req="fia-uau-5e1" ids="sel-uau-pwd"  -->
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>3</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to create, configure and delete VMs</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>4</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to set default initial VM configurations</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>5</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure virtual networks including VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FDP_VNC_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>6</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure and manage the audit system and audit data</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>7</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure VM access to physical devices</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FDP_PPR_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>8</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure inter-VM data sharing</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FDP_VMS_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>9</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td><htm:s>Ability to enable/disable VM access to Hypercall functions</htm:s></htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Management function 9 is no longer required</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>10</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure removable media policy</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FPT_RDM_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>11</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure the cryptographic functionality</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FCS_CKM.1, FCS_CKM.2, and FCS_COP.1/HASH. See also, the Functional Packages
					    for Transport Layer Security (TLS) and for Secure Shell (SSH) if claimed for methods
					    to configure their respective cryptographic functionality.</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>12</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to change default authorization factors</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FIA_PMG_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>13</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to enable/disable screen lock</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>14</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure screen lock inactivity timeout</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>15</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure remote connection inactivity timeout</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>16</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure lockout policy for unsuccessful authentication attempts through 
                                        <selectables>
                                            <selectable>timeouts between attempts</selectable>
                                            <selectable>limiting number of attempts during a time period</selectable>
                                        </selectables></htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FIA_AFL_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>17</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td><selectables>
					    <selectable id="sel-mf-dir-server">Ability to configure name/address of directory server to bind with</selectable>
					    <selectable>Not applicable</selectable></selectables></htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>S</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Must be selected if "directory-based" is selected anywhere in FIA_UAU.5.1 in the Base-PP.</htm:td>
				    <!-- sel "sel-mf-17" if req="fia-uau-5e1" ids="sel-uau-ssh-dirbased;sel-uau-pwd-dirbased; sel-uau-x509-dirbased"  -->
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>18</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure name/address of audit/logging server to which to send audit/logging records</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td> 
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FAU_STG_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>19</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure name/address of network time server</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>20</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to configure banner</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>X</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FTA_TAB.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>21</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to connect/disconnect removable devices to/from a VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>See FPT_RDM_EXT.1</htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>22</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to start a VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>23</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to stop/halt a VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>24</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to checkpoint a VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>25</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to suspend a VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>26</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>Ability to resume a VM</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>O</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td> </htm:td>
                                </htm:tr>
                                <htm:tr>
                                    <htm:td>27</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td><selectables>
					    <selectable id="sel-mf-cert-no-validity-action">Ability to configure action taken if unable to determine the validity of a certificate</selectable>
					    <selectable>Not applicable</selectable>
					    </selectables>
				    </htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>S</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>N</htm:td>
                                    <htm:td>This function must be selected if "allow the administrator to choose whether to accept the certificate in these cases"
					    in FIA_X509_EXT.2.2 in the Base-PP.</htm:td>
				    <!-- sel "sel-mf-27" if req="fia-x509-ext-2e2" ids="sel-x509-adminset"  -->
                                </htm:tr>
                           </htm:table>
						   <htm:br/>]
                        </title>
                        <ext-comp-def-title><title>
                          The TSF shall be capable of performing the following management functions
                          <assignable>description of management functions</assignable>.
                        </title></ext-comp-def-title>
                        <note role="application">
                            The ST author is expected to update <xref to="manfunc"/> with an indication as to whether any of the ‘optional’ or 
				‘selection-based’ functions are included as part of the TOE. The ST author may also omit the ‘Notes’ 
				column as it is provided in this PP-Module as an aid to the ST author in constructing the table.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
                            This SFR addresses the roles of the CC Part 2 SFRs FMT_MOF.1, FMT_SMF.1, and FMT_SMR.2.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
                            Administration is considered “local” if the Administrator is physically present at the machine on which the VS
				is installed.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
                            Administration is considered “remote” if communications between the Administrator and the Management Subsystem
				travel on a network.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
                            There is no requirement to authenticate Users of the Virtualization System. Users that have access to VMs but
				not to the Management Subsystem need not authenticate to the Virtualization System in order to use Guest
				VMs. Requirements for authentication of VM users is determined by the policies of the domains running
				within the Guest VMs.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
                        </note>
                        <aactivity>
				<TSS>
                            		The evaluator shall examine the TSS and Operational Guidance to ensure that it describes which 
					security management functions require Administrator privilege and the actions associated with each 
					management function. The evaluator shall verify that for each management function and role
					specified in the FMT_MOF_EXT.1.1 Server Virtualization Management Functions Table (Table 3),
					<!-- make this an actual table reference -->
					the defined role is able to perform all mandatory functions as well as all 
					optional or selection-based functions claimed in the ST.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
				</TSS>
				<Guidance>
	                            The evaluator shall examine the Operational Guidance to ensure that it describes how the Administrator
					or User are able to perform each management function that the ST claims the TOE supports.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
                            		The evaluator shall verify for each claimed management function that the Operational Guidance is 
					sufficiently detailed to allow the function to be performed.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
				</Guidance>
				<Tests>
	                             The evaluator shall test each management function for each role listed in the FMT_MOF_EXT.1.1 
					Server Virtualization Management Functions Table (Table 3) <!-- make this an actual table reference -->
					in the ST to demonstrate that the function can be performed by the roles that are authorized 
					to do so and the result of the function is demonstrated. The evaluator shall also verify for each
					claimed management function that if the TOE claims not to provide a
					particular role with access to the function, then it is not possible to access the TOE as that
					role and perform that function.<htm:br/><htm:br/>
				</Tests>
                        </aactivity>
                    </f-element>
		<audit-event>
			<audit-event-descr>Attempts to invoke any of the management functions listed in <xref to="manfunc"/></audit-event-descr>
			<audit-event-info>Success or failure of attempt</audit-event-info>
			<audit-event-info>Identity of actor</audit-event-info>
		</audit-event>			
                </f-component>
            </section>
	  </man-sfrs>
	    
	  <!-- 5.3 TOE Security Functional Requirements Rationale -->
          <opt-sfrs/>
	  <sel-sfrs/>
          <obj-sfrs/>
	  <impl-dep-sfrs/>
    </section>
    

    <appendix id="ent" title="Entropy">
	The TOE does not require any additional supplementary information to describe its entropy sources
	beyond the requirements outlined in the ‘Entropy Documentation and Assessment’ section of the Base
	Virtualization PP. As with other Base-PP requirements, the only additional requirement is that the
	entropy documentation also applies to the specific Server Virtualization capabilities of the TOE in
	addition to the functionality required by the Base-PP.
    </appendix>
	
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bib-base-pp">
        <tag>VirtPP</tag>
        <description>Protection Profile for Virtualization, Version: 1.1, 2021-06-14</description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
</Module>
