<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../transforms/pp2html.xsl"?>

<!--
<?xml-model href="CCProtectionProfile.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>    
-->

<!-- 
-->  

<package name="Secure Shell" 
  xmlns="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1"
  xmlns:sec="https://niap-ccevs.org/cc/v1/section"
  xmlns:h="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">

  <project-notes>
   This update turns the SSH Extended Package into a Functional Package. 

   Significant changes:

	- Removed FCS_COP and required that the PP or PP-Module that includes the package support the required algorithms. This effectively 
		eliminated the need for TD0240.
	- Incorporated TD0331
	- Incorporated TD0332
	- Incorporated TD0420
	- Incorporated TD0446
	- Added audit events covering those specified in NDcPP and a couple of the ESM PPs. These are presented as optional, and can be
		incoporated by selection in a PP or PP-module that includes this package. (TLS should do this too).   
 </project-notes>

  <PPReference>
   <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Functional Package for Secure Shell (SSH)</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>1.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2020-01-05</PPPubDate>
      <Keywords>SSH; secure shell</Keywords>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  
  <RevisionHistory>
    <entry>
      <version>1.0</version>
      <date>2021-01-05</date>
      <subject>DRAFT: First publication as a Functional Package</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
	
<!-- PP-style preferences   -->
  <pp-preferences>
<!--        <pp-pref name="display-audit-with-sfrs">0</pp-pref> -->
    <audit-events-in-sfrs/>
  </pp-preferences>

	
<!-- 			-->
<!-- 1.0 Introduction   -->
<!-- 			-->
<sec:Introduction>
	
<!-- 			-->
<!-- 1.1 Overview	-->
<!--			-->
  <sec:Overview>
        <h:p>
	    Secure Shell (SSH) is a protocol for secure remote login and other secure network services over
	    an untrusted network. SSH software can act as a client, server, or both.
      	</h:p><h:p>
	  This <h:i>Functional Package for Secure Shell</h:i> 
      	defines functional requirements for the implementation of the SSH protocol. The requirements are
      	intended to improve the security of products by enabling their evaluation. 
        </h:p>
   </sec:Overview>

<!-- 			-->
<!-- 1.2 Terms		-->
<!-- 1.2.1 Common Criteria Terms -->
<!-- 1.2.2 Technology Terms -->
<!--			-->
   <tech-terms>
	   <term abbr="SSH" full="Secure Shell">Cryptographic network protocol for initiating text-based shell sessions
		   on remote systems.</term>
   </tech-terms>
	
     
<!-- 			-->
<!-- 1.3 Compliant Targets of Evaluation	-->
<!--			-->
    <sec:toes title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation">
       <h:p>
	    The Target of Evaluation (TOE) in this Functional Package is a product which acts as an SSH client, SSH 
	    server, or both. This FP describes the extended security functionality of SSH in terms of 
     	    <citeCC/>. 
      		</h:p><h:p>
     	The contents of this Functional Package must be appropriately combined with a PP or PP-Module. When a PP or PP-Module instantiates this Package, the Package must include 
     	selection-based requirements in accordance with the selections or assignments indicated in the PP or PP-Module.
      </h:p><h:p>
        The PP or PP-Module that instantiates this Package must typically include the following components in order to satisfy dependencies of this Package. 
        It is the responsibility of the PP or PP-Module author who instantiates this Package to ensure that dependence on these components is satisfied, either by the TOE or by assumptions about its Operational Environment.
      </h:p><h:p>
      An ST must identify the applicable version of the PP or PP-Module and this
      Package in its conformance claims.
</h:p>
      <componentsneeded>
        <componentneeded>
          <componentid>FCS_CKM.1</componentid>
          <notes>To support key generation for SSH, the PP or PP-Module must
            include FCS_CKM.1 and specify the corresponding algorithm.</notes>
        </componentneeded>
        <componentneeded>
          <componentid>FCS_CKM.2</componentid>
          <notes>To support key establishment for SSH, the PP or PP-Module must
            include FCS_CKM.2 and specify the corresponding algorithm.</notes>
        </componentneeded>
        <componentneeded>
          <componentid>FCS_COP.1</componentid>
          <notes>
            To support the cryptography needed for SSH communications, the PP or PP-Module must include FCS_COP.1 (iterating as needed)
		  to specify AES with corresponding key sizes and modes, digital signature generation and verification function 
	  (at least one of RSA or ECDSA), a cryptographic hash function, and a keyed-hash message authentication function.
	  In particular, the PP or PP-Module must support AES-CTR as defined in NIST SP 800-38A with key sizes of both 128 and 256 bits.
  </notes>
</componentneeded>
<!-- The components in the PP or PP-Module that need this SFR should require it;
it is not _directly_ depended upon by this Package.-->
<componentneeded>
  <componentid>FCS_RBG_EXT.1</componentid>
  <notes>To support random bit generation needed for SSH key generation,
    the PP or PP-Module must include a requirement that specifies the TOE's ability to invoke or provide random bit generation services, commonly identified as 
    FCS_RBG_EXT.1.</notes>
</componentneeded>
<componentneeded>
  <componentid>FIA_X509_EXT.1</componentid>
  <notes>
    To support establishment of SSH communications using a public key algorithm that includes X.509, 
    the PP or PP-Module must include FIA_X509_EXT.1. Note however that support for X.509 is selectable and not mandatory.
  </notes>
</componentneeded>
<componentneeded>
  <componentid>FIA_X509_EXT.2</componentid>
  <notes>
    To support establishment of SSH communications using a public key algorithm that includes X.509, 
    the PP or PP-Module must include FIA_X509_EXT.2. Note however that support for X.509 is selectable and not mandatory.
  </notes>
</componentneeded>
<componentneeded>
  <componentid>FPT_STM.1</componentid>
  <notes>
    To support establishment of SSH communications using a public key algorithm that includes X.509, 
    the PP or PP-Module must include FPT_STM.1 or some other requirement that ensures reliable system time.  
    Note however that support for time-based rekey thresholds is selectable and not mandatory.
  </notes>
</componentneeded>
</componentsneeded>
</sec:toes>
  </sec:Introduction>
  
<!-- 			-->
<!-- 2.0 Conformance Claims	-->
<!--			-->
  <sec:Conformance_Claims>
      <!-- SME: the TLS package also uses the cclaim id="Conformance Statement" but in that 
	package, the actual text "Conformance Statement" doesn't get displayed, which is what
      	we would expect should be happening here as well (it shows up right underneath the 
	"Conformance Claimes" section header so it is redundant to display both the title and the
 	almost-identical subtitle -->
<!--
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description>This Package serves to provide Protection Profiles with additional 
          SFRs and associated Evaluation Activities specific to SSH clients and servers.  
          </h:p><h:p>
          This Package conforms to Common Criteria
          <cite linkend="bibCC" /> for Information Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1,
          Revision 5. It is CC Part 2 extended conformant.
          </h:p><h:p>
          In accordance with CC Part 1, dependencies are not included when they are addressed
          by other SFRs. The evaluation activities provide adequate proof that any dependencies are
          also satisfied.</description>
      </cclaim>
-->
	  <!--    <cclaims>
    
    </cclaims> -->
  </sec:Conformance_Claims>

<!-- 				-->
<!-- 3.0 Security Requirements 	-->
<!--				-->
	
<!-- 			-->
<!-- 3.1 Security Functional Requirements 	-->
<!--			-->
  <sec:Security_Functional_Requirements>

<!-- Audit table for mandatory requirements  -->
  <sec:ss-audit-table title="Auditable Events for Mandatory SFRs">
     <h:p>
		 The auditable events specified in this Package are included in a Security Target 
	     if the incorporating PP or PP-Module supports audit event reporting through FAU_GEN.1
		 and all other criteria in the incorporating PP or PP-Module are met.
	 </h:p>
     <audit-table table="mandatory">
       <h:div class="table-caption"><ctr ctr-type="Table" id="atref-mandatory">: Auditable Events for Mandatory SFRs</ctr></h:div>
     </audit-table>
  </sec:ss-audit-table>
	  
<!-- 			-->
<!-- 3.1.1 FCS: Cryptgraphic Support	-->
<!--			-->
<sec:cryptsup title="Cryptographic_Support_(FCS)">
	
<!-- 			-->
<!-- FCS_SSH_EXT.1	-->
<!-- Rules:
	sel-rfc5647 IF (fcs-sshc-ext1e3:sel-sshc-aes128-gcm OR fcs-sshc-ext1e3:sel-sshc-aes256-gcm OR
  			fcs-sshs-ext1e3:sel-sshs-aes128-gcm OR fcs-sshs-ext1e3:sel-sshs-aes256-gcm) AND
			(fcs-sshc-ext1e5:sel-sshc-mac-aes128-gcm OR fcs-sshc-ext1e5:sel-sshc-mac-aes256-gcm OR
  			fcs-sshs-ext1e5:sel-sshs-mac-aes128-gcm OR fcs-sshs-ext1e5:sel-sshs-mac-aes256-gcm)			
        sel-rfc5656 IF (fcs-sshc-ext-1e4:sel-sshc-ecdsa-sha2-p256 OR fcs-sshc-ext-1e4:sel-sshc-ecdsa-sha2-p384 OR
			fcs-sshs-ext-1e4:sel-sshs-ecdsa-sha2-p256 or fcs-sshs-ext-1e4:sel-sshs-ecdsa-sha2-p384) OR
			(fcs-sshc-ext-1e6:sel-sshc-ecdh-sha2-p256 OR fcs-sshc-ext-1e6:sel-sshc-ecdh-sha2-p384 OR
			fcs-sshc-ext-1e6:sel-sshc-ecdh-sha2-p521) OR
			(fcs-sshs-ext-1e6:sel-sshs-ecdh-sha2-p256 OR fcs-sshs-ext-1e6:sel-sshs-ecdh-sha2-p384 OR
			fcs-sshs-ext-1e6:sel-sshs-ecdh-sha2-p521)
        sel-rfc6187 IF fcs-sshc-ext-1e4:sel-sshc-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p256 OR fcs-sshc-ext-1e4:sel-sshc-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p384 OR
			fcs-sshs-ext-1e4:sel-sshs-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p256 OR fcs-sshs-ext-1e4:sel-sshs-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p384
	sel-rfc6668 IF fcs-sshc-ext-1.5:sel-sshc-hmac-sha2-256 OR fcs-sshc-ext-1.5:sel-sshc-hmac-sha2-512 OR
		 	fcs-sshs-ext-1.5:sel-sshs-hmac-sha2-256 OR fcs-sshs-ext-1.5:sel-sshs-hmac-sha2-512
     	sel-rfc8332 IF fcs-sshc-ext-1e4:sel-sshc-rsa-sha2-256 OR fcs-sshc-ext-1e4:sel-sshc-rsa-sha2-512 OR
			fcs-sshs-ext-1e4:sel-sshs-rsa-sha2-256 OR fcs-sshs-ext-1e4:sel-sshs-rsa-sha2-512
-->
<!--			-->	
    <f-component cc-id="fcs_ssh_ext.1" name="SSH Protocol">
	<f-element id="fcs-ssh-ext-1e1">
        <title>The TOE shall implement the SSH protocol that complies with RFCs 4251, 4252, 4253,
        4254 and 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-rfc5647">5647</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-rfc5656">5656</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-rfc6187">6187</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-rfc6668">6668</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-rfc8332">8332</selectable>
          <selectable>no other RFCs</selectable>
        </selectables> as a 
		<selectables>
		  <selectable id="ssh-client">client</selectable>
		  <selectable id="ssh-server">server</selectable>
		</selectables>.
		</title>
        <note role="application">
		<h:p>
                The ST author selects which of the additional RFCs to which
        	conformance is being claimed. An SSH product can implement additional RFCs, but only those
        	listed in the selection can be claimed as conformant under CC. 
        	The RFC selections for this requirement need to be consistent with selections in
        	later elements of this Functional Package (e.g., cryptographic algorithms permitted). 
        </h:p><h:p>
        	RFC 4253 indicates that certain cryptographic algorithms are "REQUIRED." This means that from the 
        	Internet Engineering Task Force's (IETF's) perspective the implementation must include support, not that the algorithms must 
        	be enabled for use. For the purposes of this SFR's evaluation activity and this Functional Package
        	overall, it is not necessary to ensure that algorithms listed as "REQUIRED" by the RFC 
        	but not listed in later elements of this Functional Package are actually implemented.
        </h:p><h:p>
		<!-- This says it is only selected if GCM is used for encryption AND MAC. Shouldn't it be OR? -->
         	RFC 5647 must be selected when AEAD_AES_128_GCM or AEAD_AES_256_GCM is selected as an encryption algorithm in
		FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.3 or FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.3 and as a MAC algorithm in FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.5 or FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.5.
          </h:p><h:p>
          	RFC 5656 must be selected when ecdsa-sha2-nistp256 or ecdsa-sha2-nistp384 is selected as a public key algorithm
		in FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.4 or FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.4, or when ecdh-sha2-nistp256, ecdh-sha2-nistp384, or 
		ecdh-sha2-nistp521 is selected as a key exchange algorithm in FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.6 or FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.6.
          </h:p><h:p>
          	RFC 6187 must be selected when x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp256 or x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp384 is selected as a public key 
		algorithm in FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.4 or FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.4.
          </h:p><h:p>
          	RFC 6668 must be selected when hmac-sha2-256 or hmac-sha2-512 is selected as a MAC algorithm in FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.5 or
		FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.5.
          </h:p><h:p>
          	RFC 8332 must be selected when rsa-sha2-256 or rsa-sha2-512 is selected as a public key algorithm in
		FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.4 or FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.4.
          </h:p><h:p>
        	If "client" is selected, then the ST must include FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.
        </h:p><h:p>
        	If "server" is selected, then the ST must include FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.
	</h:p>
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
		The evaluator shall ensure that the selections indicated in the ST are 
		consistent with selections in the dependent components.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
          	There are no guidance evaluation activities for this component.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
          	There are no test evaluation activities for this component.
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
	<audit-event />
      </f-component>

<!-- 			-->
<!-- FCS_SSHC_EXT.1	-->
<!--			-->	
      <f-component cc-id="fcs_sshc_ext.1" name="SSH Protocol - Client" status="sel-based">
      <selection-depends req="fcs-ssh-ext-1e1" ids="ssh-client"/>
       
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e1">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that the SSH protocol implementation supports the following
        authentication methods as described in RFC 4252: public key-based and
          <selectables>
            <selectable id="sel-pwd-based">password-based</selectable>
            <selectable>no other method</selectable>
          </selectables>.
        </title>
        <aactivity>
        <TSS>
	        The evaluator shall check to ensure that the TSS contains a description of the
        	public key algorithms that are acceptable for use for authentication and that this list
        	conforms to FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.4. The evaluator shall also ensure that 
		password-based authentication methods, if supported, are described.
        </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            If the SSH client supports password-based authentication, the evaluator shall examine the guidance to determine
		  that it includes instructions on how to configure whether the TSF uses password-based or public key-based
		  authentication.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall, for each public key algorithm supported, show that the TOE
          supports the use of that public key algorithm to authenticate a user connection to an SSH
          server. Any configuration activities required to support this test shall be performed
          according to instructions in the guidance documentation.</test>
		<test>[<h:u>conditional</h:u>]: TOE supports password-based authentication] Using the guidance documentation, the evaluator 
		  shall configure the TOE to perform password-based authentication to an SSH server, and demonstrate that
		  a user can be successfully authenticated by the TOE to an SSH server using a password as an authenticator.
		</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e2">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that, as described in RFC 4253, packets greater than 
        <assignable>number of bytes</assignable> bytes in an SSH transport connection are
        dropped.</title>
        <note role="application">
		RFC 4253 provides for the acceptance of “large packets” with the
        	caveat that the packets should be of “reasonable length” or dropped. The assignment should
        	be filled in by the ST author with the maximum packet size accepted, thus defining
        	“reasonable length” for the TOE.
	      </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
            The evaluator shall check that the TSS describes how “large packets” in terms of RFC 4253 are detected and handled.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            There are no guidance evaluation activities for this element.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            <testlist>
              The evaluator shall perform the following test:
              <test>
                The evaluator shall demonstrate that if the TOE receives a packet larger than that
                specified in this element, the packet is dropped.
              </test>
            </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e3">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that the SSH transport implementation uses the following
        encryption algorithms and rejects all other encryption algorithms: aes128-ctr, aes256-ctr, 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-aes128-cbc">aes128-cbc</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-aes256-cbc">aes256-cbc</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-aes128-gcm">AEAD_AES_128_GCM</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-aes256-gcm">AEAD_AES_256_GCM</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-aes128-gcm-openssh">aes128@openssh.com</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-aes256-gcm-openssh">aes256@openssh.com</selectable>
          <selectable>no other algorithms</selectable>
        </selectables>.
        </title>
        <note role="application">
          <h:p>
        RFC 5647 specifies the use of the AEAD_AES_128_GCM and
        AEAD_AES_256_GCM algorithms in SSH. As described in RFC 5647, AEAD_AES_128_GCM and
        AEAD_AES_256_GCM can only be chosen as encryption algorithms when the same algorithm is
        being used as the MAC algorithm.
        </h:p><h:p>If AES-GCM is selected, there should be corresponding FCS_COP entries in the ST.
	</h:p><h:p>RFC 5647 applies only to the RFC-compliant implementation of GCM. A TOE that
		implements only the “@openssh.com” variant of GCM should not select 5647-compliant 
		algorithms in FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.1. aes*-gcm@openssh.com is specified in Section 1.6 of the 
		OpenSSH Protocol Specification (https://cvsweb.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/cvsweb/src/usr.bin/ssh/PROTOCOL?rev=1.31).
        </h:p>
	</note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
          The evaluator shall check the description of the implementation of this protocol
        in the TSS to ensure that it specifies the supported encryption algorithms and any optional characteristics. 
        The evaluator shall also check the TSS to ensure that
        the encryption algorithms specified are identical to those listed for this element. 
          </TSS>
        <Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it contains
        instructions on configuring the TOE so that SSH conforms to the description in the TSS (for
        instance, the set of algorithms advertised by the TOE may have to be restricted to meet the
        requirements). 
        </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall establish an SSH connection using each of the encryption
          algorithms specified by the requirement. It is sufficient to observe (on the wire) the
          successful negotiation of the algorithm to satisfy the intent of this test.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH server to only allow the 3des-cbc encryption
          algorithm and no other encryption algorithms. The evaluator shall attempt to establish an
          SSH connection from the TOE to the SSH server and observe that the connection is
          rejected.</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
        
        <!-- SME: the NDcPP also defines aes128-gcm@openssh.com and aes256-gcm@openssh.com for FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.4 and 
	FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.4. Should those be added to this Package as well? If so, the selection "implicit" must also be
 	added to FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.6 and FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.6 -->
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e4">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that the SSH transport implementation uses 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-rsa">ssh-rsa</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-rsa-sha2-256">rsa-sha2-256</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-rsa-sha2-512">rsa-sha2-512</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-ecdsa-sha2-p256">ecdsa-sha2-nistp256</selectable>
        </selectables> and 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-ecdsa-sha2-p384">ecdsa-sha2-nistp384</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p256">x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp256</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p384">x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp384</selectable>
          <selectable>no other public key algorithms</selectable>
        </selectables> as its public key algorithm(s) and rejects all other public key
        algorithms.</title>
        <note role="application">
        <h:p>Implementations that select only ssh-rsa will not achieve the
        112-bit security strength in the digital signature generation for SSH authentication as is
        recommended in NIST SP 800-131A. 
        
        <!-- SME: should this statement be kept as-is, withdrawn, or incorporated into the SFR? -->
        Future versions of this document may remove ssh-rsa as a selection. 
        
        If "x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp256" or "x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp384" are selected, then
        the list of trusted certification authorities must be selected in 
        FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.8. RFC 8332 specifies the use of rsa-sha2-256 or rsa-sha2-512 in SSH.
        </h:p><h:p>
        The SFRs for cryptographic key generation and certificate validation are inherited
        from the PP or PP-Module that includes this Package.
        </h:p>
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
            The evaluator shall check the description of the implementation of this protocol
            in the TSS to ensure that it specifies the supported public key algorithms and any optional characteristics. 
            The evaluator shall also check the TSS to ensure that
            the encryption algorithms specified are identical to those listed for this element. 
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it contains
        instructions on configuring the TOE so that SSH conforms to the description in the TSS (for
        instance, the set of algorithms advertised by the TOE may have to be restricted to meet the
        requirements). 
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall establish a SSH connection using each of the public key
          algorithms specified by the requirement to authenticate an SSH server to the TOE. It is
          sufficient to observe (on the wire) the successful negotiation of the algorithm to
          satisfy the intent of the test.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH server to only allow the ssh-dsa public key
          algorithm and no other public key algorithms. The evaluator shall attempt to establish an
          SSH connection from the TOE to the SSH server and observe that the connection is
          rejected.</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e5">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that the SSH transport implementation uses 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-hmac-sha1">hmac-sha1</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-hmac-sha1-96">hmac-sha1-96</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-hmac-sha2-256">hmac-sha2-256</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-hmac-sha2-512">hmac-sha2-512</selectable>
        </selectables> and 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-mac-aes128-gcm">AEAD_AES_128_GCM</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-mac-aes256-gcm">AEAD_AES_256_GCM</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshc-implicit">implicit</selectable>		
          <selectable>no other MAC algorithms</selectable>
        </selectables> as its data integrity MAC algorithm(s) and rejects all other MAC
        algorithm(s).</title>
        <note role="application">
          <h:p>
            RFC 5647 specifies the use of the AEAD_AES_128_GCM and
        AEAD_AES_256_GCM algorithms in SSH. As described in RFC 5647, AEAD_AES_128_GCM and
        AEAD_AES_256_GCM can only be chosen as MAC algorithms when the same algorithm is being used
        as the encryption algorithm. RFC 6668 specifies the use of the sha2 algorithms in
        SSH.
        </h:p><h:p>
        The SFRs for cryptographic operations, encryption, and hashing are inherited from  
        the PP or PP-Module that includes this Package.
	</h:p><h:p>The ST author selects “implicit” if and only if aes*-gcm@openssh.com is selected 
		as an encryption algorithm. When aes*-gcm@openssh.com is negotiated as the encryption 
		algorithm, the MAC algorithm field is ignored and GCM is implicitly used as the MAC. 
		“implicit” is not an SSH algorithm identifier and will not be seen on the wire; 
		however, the negotiated MAC might be decoded as “implicit”.
        </h:p>
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
          The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure that it lists the supported data
        integrity algorithms and that this list corresponds to the list in this element. 
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it includes
        instructions to the administrator on how to ensure that only the allowed data integrity
        algorithms are used in SSH connections with the TOE (specifically, that the “none” MAC
        algorithm is not allowed). 
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall establish a SSH connection using each of the integrity
          algorithms specified by the requirement. It is sufficient to observe (on the wire) the
          successful negotiation of the algorithm to satisfy the intent of this test.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH server to only allow the “none” MAC algorithm.
          The evaluator shall attempt to connect from the TOE to the SSH server and observe that the
          attempt fails.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH server to only allow the hmac-md5 MAC
          algorithm. The evaluator shall attempt to connect from the TOE to the SSH server and
          observe that the attempt fails. To ensure the proposed MAC algorithm is used, the evaluator 
		shall ensure a non-aes*- gcm@openssh.com encryption algorithm is negotiated while 
		performing this test.</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e6">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that 
          <selectables>
            <selectable id="sel-sshc-dhg14-sha1">diffie-hellman-group14-sha1</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshc-ecdh-sha2-p256">ecdh-sha2-nistp256</selectable>
          </selectables>
          and
          <selectables>
            <selectable id="sel-sshc-ecdh-sha2-p384">ecdh-sha2-nistp384</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshc-ecdh-sha2-p521">ecdh-sha2-nistp521</selectable>
            <selectable>no other methods</selectable>
          </selectables>
        are the only allowed key exchange methods used for the SSH protocol.</title>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
          The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure that it lists the supported key
        exchange algorithms and that this list corresponds to the list in this element. 
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
          The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it includes
        instructions to the administrator on how to ensure that only the allowed key exchange
        algorithms are used in SSH connections with the TOE. 
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following test:
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH server to permit all allowed key exchange
          methods. The evaluator shall then attempt to connect from the TOE to the SSH server using each
          allowed key exchange method and observe that each attempt succeeds.</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e7">
        <title>The SSH client shall ensure that the SSH connection be rekeyed after 
          <selectables>
            <selectable>no more than 2<h:sup>28</h:sup> packets have been transmitted</selectable>
            <selectable>no more than 1 gigabyte of data has been transmitted</selectable>
            <selectable>no more than 1 hour</selectable>
          </selectables>
          using that key.</title>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
            There are no TSS evaluation activities for this element.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            There are no guidance evaluation activities for this element.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following test for each rekeying method claimed in the ST:
          <testlist>  <!-- Incorporates TD 0331 -->
            The evaluator shall perform the following test:
            <test>The evaluator will configure the TOE to create a log entry when a rekey occurs. The evaluator will connect to the TOE with
		    an SSH client and cause a rekey to occur according to the selection(s) in the ST, and subsequently the evaluator uses
		    available methods and tools to verify that rekeying occurs. This could be done, e.g., by checking that a corresponding audit
		    event has been generated by the TOE, if the TOE supports auditing of rekey events. 
            </test>
          </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshc-ext-1e8">
          <title>The SSH client shall ensure that the SSH client authenticates the identity of the SSH server
            using a local database associating each host name with its corresponding public key or 
            <selectables>
              <selectable id="sel-sshc-trustedCAs">a list of trusted certification authorities</selectable>
              <selectable>no other methods</selectable>
            </selectables> as described in RFC 4251 section 4.1.</title>
          <note role="application"> The selection for "a list of trusted certification authorities" can only be chosen
            if "x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp256" or "x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp384" are selected in 
            FCS_SSHC_EXT.1.4.</note>
          <aactivity>
            <TSS>
              There are no TSS evaluation activities for this element.
            </TSS>
            <Guidance>
              There are no guidance evaluation activities for this element.
            </Guidance>
            <Tests>
              The evaluator shall perform the following tests: 
            <testlist>
              <test>The evaluator shall delete all entries in the TOE’s list of recognized SSH server
                host keys and, if selected, all entries in the TOE’s list of trusted certification
                authorities. The evaluator shall then initiate a connection from the TOE to an SSH server.
                The evaluator shall ensure that the TOE either rejects the connection or displays the
                SSH server’s public key (either the key bytes themselves or a hash of the key using any
                allowed hash algorithm) and prompts the user to accept or deny the key before
                continuing the connection.</test>
              <test>The evaluator shall add an entry associating a host name with a public key into
                the TOE’s local database. The evaluator shall then replace, on the corresponding SSH server,
                the server’s host key with a different host key. The evaluator shall initiate a
                connection from the TOE to the SSH server using password-based authentication, shall
                ensure that the TOE rejects the connection, and shall ensure that the password was not
                transmitted to the SSH server (for example, by instrumenting the SSH server with a
                debugging capability to output received passwords).</test>
            </testlist>
              </Tests>
          </aactivity>
       </f-element>
       <audit-event type="optional">
		<audit-event-descr>Failure to establish a session</audit-event-descr>
	       	<audit-event-info>Reason for failure.</audit-event-info>
	       	<audit-event-info>Non-TOE endpoint of attempted connection (IP Address).</audit-event-info>
       </audit-event>
       <audit-event type="optional">
		<audit-event-descr>Establishment of a session</audit-event-descr>
	       	<audit-event-info>Non-TOE endpoint of connection (IP Address).</audit-event-info>
       </audit-event>
       <audit-event type="optional">
		<audit-event-descr>Termination of a session</audit-event-descr>
	       	<audit-event-info>Non-TOE endpoint of connection (IP Address).</audit-event-info>
       </audit-event>
      </f-component>

<!-- 			-->
<!-- FCS_SSHS_EXT.1	-->
<!--			-->	
    <f-component cc-id="fcs_sshs_ext.1" name="SSH Protocol - Server" status="sel-based">
      <selection-depends req="fcs-ssh-ext-1e1" ids="ssh-server"/>
      
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e1"> 
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that the SSH protocol implementation supports the following
        authentication methods as described in RFC 4252: public key-based and
          <selectables>
            <selectable>password-based</selectable>
            <selectable>no other method</selectable>
          </selectables>.
        </title>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
          The evaluator shall check to ensure that the TSS contains a description of the
        public key algorithms that are acceptable for use for authentication and that this list
        conforms to 
        FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.4. The evaluator shall also ensure that password-based authentication
        methods, if supported, are described.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            If the SSH server supports password-based authentication, the evaluator shall examine the guidance to determine that it includes instructions on how to configure whether the TSF uses password-based or public key-based authentication.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall, for each public key algorithm supported, show that the TOE
          supports the use of that public key algorithm to authenticate a user connection from an
          SSH client. Any configuration activities required to support this test shall be performed
          according to instructions in the guidance documentation.</test>
          <test>
          The evaluator shall choose one public key algorithm supported by the
          TOE. The evaluator shall generate a new key pair for that algorithm without
          configuring the TOE to recognize the public key for authentication. The
          evaluator shall use an SSH client to attempt to connect to the TOE with the
          new key pair and demonstrate that authentication fails.
          </test>
		<test>[<h:u>conditional</h:u>]: TOE supports password-based authentication] Using the guidance documentation, the evaluator shall configure the TOE to perform
          password-based authentication on a client and demonstrate that a user can be
          successfully authenticated by the TOE using a password as an authenticator.</test>
          <test>
            [<h:u>conditional</h:u>]: TOE supports password-based authentication] The evaluator shall use an SSH client to enter an incorrect password to
            attempt to authenticate to the TOE and demonstrate that the authentication
            fails.
          </test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e2">
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that, as described in RFC 4253, packets greater than 
        <assignable>number of bytes</assignable> bytes in an SSH transport connection are
        dropped.</title>
        <note role="application">RFC 4253 provides for the acceptance of “large packets” with the
        caveat that the packets should be of “reasonable length” or dropped. The assignment should
        be filled in by the ST author with the maximum packet size accepted, thus defining
        “reasonable length” for the TOE.</note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>The evaluator shall check that the TSS describes how “large packets” in terms of
        RFC 4253 are detected and handled.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            There are no guidance evaluation activities for this element.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
        <testlist>
          The evaluator shall perform the following test:
          <test>
        The evaluator shall demonstrate that if the TOE receives a packet larger than that
        specified in this element, the packet is dropped.
          </test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e3">
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that the SSH transport implementation uses the following
          encryption algorithms and rejects all other encryption algorithms: aes128-ctr, 
          aes256-ctr, <selectables>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-aes128-cbc">aes128-cbc</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-aes256-cbc">aes256-cbc</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-aes128-gcm">AEAD_AES_128_GCM</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-aes256-gcm">AEAD_AES_256_GCM</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-aes128-gcm-openssl">aes128-gcm@openssh.com</selectable>	
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-aes256-gcm-openssl">aes256-gcm@openssh.com</selectable>	
            <selectable>no other algorithms</selectable>
          </selectables>.
        </title>
        <note role="application">
          <h:p>
          RFC 5647 specifies the use of the AEAD_AES_128_GCM and AEAD_AES_256_GCM
          algorithms in SSH. As described in RFC 5647, AEAD_AES_128_GCM and
          AEAD_AES_256_GCM can only be chosen as encryption algorithms when the same
          algorithm is being used as the MAC algorithm.
	  </h:p><h:p>RFC 5647 applies only to the RFC compliant implementation of GCM. A TOE that  
		implements only the “@openssh.com” variant of GCM should not select 5647-compliant 
		algorithms in FCS_SSHS_EXT.1.1. aes*-gcm@openssh.com is specified in Section 1.6 of the 
		OpenSSH Protocol Specification (https://cvsweb.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/cvsweb/src/usr.bin/ssh/PROTOCOL?rev=1.31).
        </h:p>
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
 	The evaluator shall check the description of the implementation of this protocol
        in the TSS to ensure that it specifies the supported encryption algorithms and any optional characteristics. 
        The evaluator shall also check the TSS to ensure that
        the encryption algorithms specified are identical to those listed for this element.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it contains
            instructions on configuring the TOE so that SSH conforms to the description in the TSS (for
            instance, the set of algorithms advertised by the TOE may have to be restricted to meet the
            requirements). 
          </Guidance>
        <Tests>
          The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>The evaluator shall initiate an SSH connection using each of the encryption
          algorithms specified by the requirement. It is sufficient to observe (on the wire) the
          successful negotiation of the algorithm to satisfy the intent of this test.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH client to only propose the 3des-cbc encryption
          algorithm and no other encryption algorithms. The evaluator shall attempt to establish an
          SSH connection from this client to the TOE server and observe that the connection is
          rejected.</test>
        </testlist>
        </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e4">
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that the SSH transport implementation uses 
          <selectables>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-rsa">ssh-rsa</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-rsa-sha2-256">rsa-sha2-256</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-rsa-sha2-512">rsa-sha2-512</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-ecdsa-sha2-p256">ecdsa-sha2-nistp256</selectable>
          </selectables>
           and 
          <selectables>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-ecdsa-sha2-p384">ecdsa-sha2-nistp384</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-x508v3-ecdsa-sha2-p256">x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp256</selectable>
            <selectable id="sel-sshs-x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-p384">x509v3-ecdsa-sha2-nistp384</selectable>
            <selectable>no other public key algorithms</selectable>
          </selectables>
        as its public key algorithm(s) and
        rejects all other public key algorithms.
        </title>
        <note role="application">
          <h:p>
          Implementations that select only ssh-rsa will not achieve the 112-bit security strength in the
          digital signature generation for SSH authentication as is recommended in NIST SP 800-131A. 
          
          <!-- SME: should this statement be kept as-is, withdrawn, or incorporated into the SFR? -->
          Future versions of this document may remove ssh-rsa as a selection.  
          
          RFC 8332 specifies the use of rsa-sha2-256 or rsa-sha2-512 in SSH.
          </h:p><h:p>
          The SFRs for cryptographic key generation and certificate validation are inherited
          from the PP or PP-Module that includes this Package.
          </h:p>
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
            The evaluator shall check the description of the implementation of this protocol
            in the TSS to ensure that it specifies the supported public key algorithms and any optional characteristics. 
            The evaluator shall also check the TSS to ensure that
            the encryption algorithms specified are identical to those listed for this element. 
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it contains
            instructions on configuring the TOE so that SSH conforms to the description in the TSS (for
            instance, the set of algorithms advertised by the TOE may have to be restricted to meet the
            requirements). 
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>Using an appropriately configured client, the evaluator shall establish an SSH
          connection using each of the public key algorithms specified by the requirement to
          authenticate to the TOE. It is sufficient to observe (on the wire) the successful negotiation of the
          algorithm to satisfy the intent of this test.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH client to propose only the ssh-dsa public key
          algorithm and no other public key algorithms. Using this client, the evaluator shall
          attempt to establish an SSH connection to the TOE and observe that the connection is
          rejected.</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e5">
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that the SSH transport implementation uses 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-hmac-sha1">hmac-sha1</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-hmac-sha1-96">hmac-sha1-96</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-hmac-sha2-256">hmac-sha2-256</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-hmac-sha2-512">hmac-sha2-512</selectable>
        </selectables>
          and
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-mac-aes128-gcm">AEAD_AES_128_GCM</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-mac-aes256-gcm">AEAD_AES_256_GCM</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-implicit">implicit</selectable>		
          <selectable>no other MAC algorithms</selectable>
        </selectables>
        as its MAC algorithm(s) and rejects all
        other MAC algorithm(s).</title>
        <note role="application">
          <h:p>
          RFC 5647 specifies the use of the AEAD_AES_128_GCM and AEAD_AES_256_GCM
          algorithms in SSH. As described in RFC 5647, AEAD_AES_128_GCM and
          AEAD_AES_256_GCM can only be chosen as MAC algorithms when the same algorithm is
          being used as the encryption algorithm. RFC 6668 specifies the use of the sha2 algorithms
          in SSH.
          </h:p><h:p>
          The SFRs for cryptographic operations, encryption and hashing, are inherited from the PP or PP-Module that includes this Package.
	  </h:p><h:p>The ST author selects “implicit” if and only if aes*-gcm@openssh.com is selected as an 
		encryption algorithm. When aes*-gcm@openssh.com is negotiated as the encryption
		algorithm, the MAC algorithm field is ignored and GCM is implicitly used as the MAC.
		“implicit” is not an SSH algorithm identifier and will not be seen on the wire; however,
		the negotiated MAC might be decoded as “implicit”.	
           </h:p>
        </note>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
          The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure that it lists the supported data
        integrity algorithms and that this list corresponds to the list in this element. 
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it includes
        instructions to the administrator on how to ensure that only the allowed data integrity
        algorithms are used in SSH connections with the TOE (specifically, that the “none” and "hmac-md5" MAC
        algorithms are not allowed). 
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>Using an appropriately configured client, the evaluator shall establish a SSH
          connection with the TOE using each of the integrity algorithms specified by the requirement. It is
          sufficient to observe (on the wire) the successful negotiation of the algorithm to
          satisfy the intent of the test.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH client to only propose the “none” MAC
          algorithm. Using this client, the evaluator shall attempt to connect to the TOE and
          observe that the attempt fails.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH client to only propose the hmac-md5 MAC
          algorithm. Using this client, the evaluator shall attempt to connect to the TOE and
          observe that the attempt fails. To ensure the proposed MAC algorithm is used, the
		  evaluator shall ensure a non-aes*- gcm@openssh.com encryption algorithm is negotiated 
		  while performing this test.
		</test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e6">
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that 
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-dhg14-sha1">diffie-hellman-group14-sha1</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-ecdh-sha2-p256">ecdh-sha2-nistp256</selectable>
        </selectables>
          and
        <selectables>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-ecdh-sha2-p384">ecdh-sha2-nistp384</selectable>
          <selectable id="sel-sshs-ecdh-sha2-p521">ecdh-sha2-nistp521</selectable>
          <selectable>no other methods</selectable>
        </selectables>
        are the only allowed key exchange
        methods used for the SSH protocol.</title>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>The evaluator shall check the TSS to ensure that it lists the supported key
        exchange algorithms and that this list corresponds to the list in this element.
          </TSS>
        <Guidance>
          The evaluator shall check the guidance documentation to ensure that it includes
        instructions to the administrator on how to ensure that only the allowed key exchange
        algorithms are used in SSH connections to the TOE. 
        </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following tests:
        <testlist>
          <test>For each of the allowed key exchange methods, the evaluator shall configure an SSH
          client to propose only that method and then attempt to connect to the TOE. The evaluator shall confirm that each attempt
          succeeds.</test>
          <test>The evaluator shall configure an SSH client to only allow the diffie-hellman-group1-sha1
            key exchange. The evaluator shall attempt to use this SSH client to connect to the TOE and confirm that this attempt fails.
            </test>
        </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
      <f-element id="fcs-sshs-ext-1e7">
        <title>The SSH server shall ensure that the SSH connection be rekeyed after 
          <selectables>
            <selectable>no more than 2<h:sup>28</h:sup> packets have been transmitted</selectable>
            <selectable>no more than 1 gigabyte of data has been transmitted</selectable>
            <selectable>no more than 1 hour</selectable>
          </selectables>
         using that key.</title>
        <aactivity>
          <TSS>
            There are no TSS evaluation activities for this element.
          </TSS>
          <Guidance>
            If the TOE has the ability to generate a log when an SSH rekey occurs, the evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to verify that it describes any configuration that is needed for this to be performed.
          </Guidance>
          <Tests>
            The evaluator shall perform the following test for each rekeying method claimed in the ST:
          <testlist>  <!-- Incorporates TD 0331 -->
            The evaluator shall perform the following test:
            <test>The evaluator will configure the TOE to create a log entry when a rekey occurs. The evaluator will connect to the TOE with
		    an SSH client and cause a rekey to occur according to the selection(s) in the ST, and subsequently the evaluator uses
		    available methods and tools to verify that rekeying occurs. This could be done, e.g., by checking that a corresponding audit
		    event has been generated by the TOE, if the TOE supports auditing of rekey events. 
            </test>
	  </testlist>
          </Tests>
        </aactivity>
      </f-element>
       <audit-event type="optional">
		<audit-event-descr>Failure to establish a session</audit-event-descr>
	       	<audit-event-info>Reason for failure.</audit-event-info>
	       	<audit-event-info>Non-TOE endpoint of attempted connection (IP Address).</audit-event-info>
       </audit-event>
       <audit-event type="optional">
		<audit-event-descr>Establishment of a session</audit-event-descr>
	       	<audit-event-info>Non-TOE endpoint of connection (IP Address).</audit-event-info>
       </audit-event>
       <audit-event type="optional">
		<audit-event-descr>Termination of a session</audit-event-descr>
	       	<audit-event-info>Non-TOE endpoint of connection (IP Address).</audit-event-info>
       </audit-event>
    </f-component>
  </sec:cryptsup>

	</sec:Security_Functional_Requirements>
  
<!--                    -->
<!-- Appendix A: Optional Requirements 	-->
<!--                    -->
	
    <appendix id="appendix-optional-plus" title="Optional Requirements">  

    <!-- Contents of the appendix are totally generated by "optional-appendix-plus" xsl template. 
         Includes boilerplate, headers, audit table. So the below is not needed. But there is is. -->
    <!--    <audit-table table="optional">
	  Auditable events for Optional SFRs:<h:br/><h:br/>
	</audit-table>  -->
    </appendix> 

<!--                    -->
<!-- Appendix B: Selection-based Requirements 	-->
<!--                    -->

    <appendix id="appendix-sel-based" title="Selection-Based Requirements"> 
       
    <!-- Contents of the appendix are totally generated by "optional-appendix" xsl template. 
         Includes boilerplate, headers, audit table. So the below is not needed. But there is is. -->
    <!--    <audit-table table="sel-based">
	  Auditable events for Selecton-based Requirements:	
	</audit-table>   -->
    </appendix> 
	
<!--                    -->
<!-- Appendix C: References 	-->
<!--                    -->
	
  <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
    <bibliography>
     <entry id="bibGPOS">
        <tag>GPOSPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=442">Protection Profile for General 
            Purpose Operating Systems
            </h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibMDM">
        <tag>MDMPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=428">Protection Profile for Mobile 
            Device Management
          </h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibAppPP">
        <tag>AppPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=429">Protection Profile for Application
            Software</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibVirt">
        <tag>VirtPP</tag>
        <description>
          <h:a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/Profile/Info.cfm?id=408">Protection Profile for 
            Virtualization</h:a>
        </description>
      </entry>   
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>

<!--                    -->
<!-- Appendix D: Acronyms	-->
<!--                    -->
  <appendix id="acronyms" title="Acronyms">
      <acronyms/>
  </appendix>

</package>
